“我的语言里没有这些音。”这无疑是真的，不过
We don't have some of those sounds in my language. This is undoubtedly true, but
你可以看到，你只需要掌握有限几个新音：ah、ah、
you can see that you only need to pick up a limited number of new sounds, ah, ah,
ah、uh、uh。以你已经掌握过的能力来看，这并不是大问题。
ah, uh, uh. Given what you've already accomplished in life, this is not a big
一位中文母语者曾抱怨 R 音对他说有多难。
deal. A Chinese speaker was once bemoaning how hard it was for him to say the R. When
他回答说：“当然，我有物理学博士学位。”
asked if he went to college, he said, of course, I have a PhD in physics from
他停了一下，意识到相比之下，R 并不难。
Caltech. After a beat, he realized that, compared to that, the R is not hard. Other
至于其他文字系统，如果你使用其中一种，就把它和英语比较一下。
characters. If you use one of these character sets, compare it with English.
让我简单地解释为什么我们使用这些声音。
Let me give a quick explanation of why we're using these sounds. When you come in
通过自己的语言来看，你原本处在一个完全绝对的参照体系里。
through your own language, you're coming from a place of total and absolute
你已经会这个声音，所以我们是拿你知道的东西，横向迁移到
confidence. You know that sound, so we're taking something you know and doing a
英语的一组字母上。另一方面，如果你开始使用英语字母
lateral transference to a set of letters in English. If on the other hand you start
如果从零开始，你会一直怀疑自己做得对不对，这会消耗你的
from scratch, you'll be wondering if you're doing it right and this will drain
现在你已经努力练习，并且成功地
your confidence and your energy. Now that you've worked hard and successfully
模仿这些声音之后，就可以进入下一步，也就是常规
imitated the sounds, you're going to go on to the next step, which is regular
转移到英语的一组字母上。
spelling.